<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MahaTourGuide</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="forts">Forts</string>
    <string name="temples">Temples</string>
    <string name="dams">Dams</string>
    <string name="zoos">Zoos</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="raigad_short">\"Raigad (Marathi:रायगड) is a hill fort situated in Mahad, Raigad district of Maharashtra, India. \"</string>
    <string name="raigad_description">Raigad (Marathi:रायगड) is a hill fort situated in Mahad, Raigad district of Maharashtra, India. The Raigad Fort, formerly known as Rairi, was built by Chandraraoji More, the King of Jawali, who was then seized by Shivaji who made it his capital in 1674 when he was crowned the King of a Maratha Kingdom which later developed into the Maratha Empire, eventually covering much of western and central India.[1] The fort rises 820 metres (2,700 ft) above the sea level and is located in the Sahyadri mountain range. There are approximately 1737 steps leading to the fort. The Raigad Ropeway, an aerial tramway exists to reach the top of the fort in 10 minutes. The fort was looted and destroyed by the British after it was captured in 1818.</string>
    <string name="sinhgad_short">Sinhagad is a hill fortress located at around 35 km southwest of the city of Pune, India. Some of the information available at this fort suggests that the fort could have been built 2000 years ago.</string>
    <string name="sinhgad_description">"Sinhagad is a hill fortress located at around 35 km southwest of the city of Pune, India. Some of the information available at this fort suggests that the fort could have been built 2000 years ago. The caves and the carvings in the Kaundinyeshwar temple stand as proofs for the same.  Previously known as Kondhana, the fort had been the site of many battles, most notably the Battle of Sinhagad in 1670. Perched on an isolated cliff of the Bhuleswar range in the Sahyadri Mountains, the fort is situated on a hill about 760 metres above ground and 1,312 metres above mean sea level.[citation needed]  The Sinhagad (Lion's Fort) was strategically built to provide natural protection due to its very steep slopes. The walls and bastions were constructed only at key places. There are two gates to enter the fort, the Kalyan Darwaza and Pune Darwaza which are positioned at the south east and north-east ends respectively.[1] The fort was also strategically located at the centre of a string of other Maratha Empire forts such as Rajgad Fort, Purandar Fort and Torna Fort. "</string>
    <string name="pratapgad_short">Pratapgad (Marathi: प्रतापगड) literally \'Valour Fort\' is a large fort located in Satara district, in the Western Indian state of Maharashtra. Significant as the site of the Battle of Pratapgad, the fort is now a popular tourist destination.</string>
    <string name="pratapgad_description">"Pratapgad (Marathi: प्रतापगड) literally 'Valour Fort' is a large fort located in Satara district, in the Western Indian state of Maharashtra. Significant as the site of the Battle of Pratapgad, the fort is now a popular tourist destination. Pratapgad fort is located 15 kilometres (9.3 mi) from Poladpur and 23 kilometres (14 mi) west of Mahabaleshwar, a popular hill station in the area. The fort stands 1,080 metres (3,540 ft) above sea level[1] and is built on a spur which overlooks the road between the villages of Par and Kinesvar. "</string>
    <string name="panhala_short">Panhala is a city and a Hill station Municipal Council 18 km northwest of Kolhapur, in Kolhapur district in the Indian state of Maharashtra.</string>
    <string name="panhala_description">"Panhala fort (also known as Panhalgad, Panhalla (literally \"the home of serpents\")), is located in Panhala, 20 kilometres northwest of Kolhapur in Maharashtra, India. It is strategically located looking over a pass in the Sahyadri mountain range which was a major trade route from Bijapur in the interior of Maharashtra to the coastal areas.[1] Due to its strategic location, it was the centre of several skirmishes in the Deccan involving the Marathas, the Mughals and the British East India Company, the most notable being the Battle of Pavan Khind. Here, the queen regent of Kolhapur, Tarabai, spent her formative years. Several parts of the fort and the structures within are still intact. "</string>
    <string name="shirdi_short">Located approximately 258 km from Mumbai, shirdi sai baba temple maharashtra is one of the most popular temples here.</string>
    <string name="shirdi_description">Located approximately 258 km from Mumbai, shirdi sai baba temple maharashtra is one of the most popular temples here. Known for being the Land of Sai, Shirdi attracts thousands of devotees every year because of the Shirdi Temple. This temple is dedicated to Sai Baba who is considered to be one of the greatest saints in the country. After visiting Shirdi at the age of 16 years, Sai Baba stayed at this village where he attained Samadhi as well. Spread across 200 square meters, the temple complex today consists of Chavadi, Samadhi Mandir, Gurusthan, Lendi Baug and more.</string>
    <string name="grishneshwar_short">Located in Aurangabad district of Maharashtra, Grishneshwar Jyotirlinga Temple is one of the most popular temples in Maharashtra.</string>
    <string name="grishneshwar_description">Located in Aurangabad district of Maharashtra, Grishneshwar Jyotirlinga Temple is one of the most popular temples in Maharashtra. Being dedicated to Lord Shiva, this temple is home to one of the jyotirlingas mentioned in the Shiva Purana. Believed to be the 12th jyotirlinga, Shiva at this temple is known by different names such as Kusumeswarar, Ghushmeswara, Ghrushmeswara and Grishneswara. The temple went through several reconstructions during the reign of Maloji Raje Bhosale and Rani Ahilyabhai Holkar. Built with red volcanic rock, this temple is often recognized for its fine medieval architecture and 5-tier Shikara. Today the temple contains a garbhagriha, an antarala and a sabha mandapa. Many devotees visit this temple during the Maha Shivaratri which is a significantly important religious festival at this jyotirling temple in maharashtra.</string>
    <string name="trimbakeshwar_short">Located in Nashik, Trimbakeshwar Jyotirlinga temple in maharashtra is dedicated to Lord Shiva.</string>
    <string name="trimbakeshwar_description">Located in Nashik, Trimbakeshwar Jyotirlinga temple in maharashtra is dedicated to Lord Shiva. Built by Peshwa Balaji Baji Rao, this temple is home to the Kushavarta which is known for being the source of the Godavari river. Surrounded by the lush greenery of the Anjaneri Mountain, this temple has three lingams of Shiva, Vishnu, and Brahma. You will also find three water bodies here i.e. Bilva Theertha, Viswananthirtha and Mukundathirtha. Being one of the best temples in maharashtra, the Jyotirlinga here depicts three faces i.e. Lord Brahma, Lord Vishnu, and Lord Rudra. The jeweled crown that covers the lingas is displayed in between 4 pm and 5 pm on every Monday. This crown is believed to exist from the age of Pandavas.</string>
    <string name="jejuri_short">Jejuri Temple is located in the Jejuri town, which lies to the ... revered temples in the state, known as the Khandobachi Jejuri.</string>
    <string name="jejuri_description">\"Jejuri Temple is located in the Jejuri town, which lies to the southeast of the Pune city of Maharashtra. The town is known for being the venue of one of the revered temples in the state, known as the Khandobachi Jejuri.[12] The temple is dedicated to Khandoba, also known as Mhalsakant or Malhari Martand or Mylaralinga. Khandoba is regarded as the \'God of Jejuri\' and is held in great reverence by the Dhangars. The temple was the site of a historic treaty between Tarabai and Balaji Bajirao on 14 September 1752. Jejuri Khandoba Temple can be easily divided into two separate sections - the Mandap and Garbhagriha. \"</string>
    <string name="khadakwasla_short">The dam is constructed on River Mutha which is the source of water supply in Pune and its suburban regions.</string>
    <string name="khadakwasla_description">\"An eminent tourist attraction, Khadakwasla Dam is a pleasant sight to behold. Built with state-of-the-art engineering, it is located on the outskirts of Pune. The dam is constructed on River Mutha which is the source of water supply in Pune and its suburban regions. Khadakwasla forms a reservoir, called Khadakwasla Lake which is a perfect spot for a pleasant getaway. The reservoir occupies around 22,000 square kilometres area and runs 35 metres deep. As the stream runs down the cliff, it resembles a heavy rush of water flowing effortlessly down the dam. In the nearby region, the well-known National Defence Academy and Central Water and Power Research Station (CWPRS) are situated. You’ll find Sinhagad Fort and Karla Caves which are known as one of the ancient places to explore artefacts from a thousand years ago. \"</string>
    <string name="bhandardara_short">Bhandardara Dam also known as Wilson Dam has its existence on Pravara River and is situated 150 metres above ground level.</string>
    <string name="bhandardara_description">Bhandardara Dam also known as Wilson Dam has its existence on Pravara River and is situated 150 metres above ground level. This dam is located in holiday resort village of Bhandardara on the western coast of India. This lies in Ahmednagar district of Maharashtra.Arthur Lake is formed due to the construction of Wilson Dam and is fed by Pravara River. This lake is also known as Lake Arthur Hill or Bhandardara Lake.Bhandardara is among the major tourist attractions in India and has the presence of natural beauty, waterfalls, mountains, greenery, invigorating air and pristine ambience.</string>
    <string name="koyna_short">The Koyna Dam is built on Koyana River that originates from Mahabaleshwar and is nestled between the Sahyadris in the Western Ghats.</string>
    <string name="jayakwadi_short">One of the largest irrigation projects in Maharashtra, Jayakwadi Dam is a multipurpose project which aims to irrigate drought-prone Marathwada Region</string>
    <string name="jayakwadi_description">One of the largest irrigation projects in Maharashtra, Jayakwadi Dam is a multipurpose project which aims to irrigate drought-prone Marathwada Region and also to provide water for drinking and industrial usage. Built across Godavari River, its height is approximately 41.30 m and length of 9,998 metres with a total storage capacity 2,909 MCM. Jayakwadi Bird Sanctuary and Dnyaneshwar Dam in the surrounding area make the dam a perfect site to escape the chaos of city life and reminisce the serenity. Dnyaneshwar Udyan is one of the largest gardens in Maharashtra resembling the Brindavan Gardens of Mysore. Close to it is the bird sanctuary which is the abode of many resident and migratory birds. For bird lovers and nature buffs, Jayakwadi Dam is surely heaven.\n</string>
    <string name="koyna_description">\" The Koyna Dam is built on Koyana River that originates from Mahabaleshwar and is nestled between the Sahyadris in the Western Ghats. The massive structure is spread across 891 square km. The drive from Chiplun this place goes through majestic dense forests, plateaus, lush green meadows and scintillating Navna waterfalls. It is not allowed to visit the dam, however, the travellers can take permission letter which is issued in Pune. Spending the sunrise and sunset by the Koyna dam and its surrounding Nehru Park or staying at MTDC\'s Koyana Resort. is one of the popular things to do.\"</string>
    <string name="amte_short">Padma Shri award winner and social worker Dr. Prakash Amte set up this animal ark that houses orphaned wild animals.</string>
    <string name="amte_description">Padma Shri award winner and social worker Dr. Prakash Amte set up this animal ark that houses orphaned wild animals. All the animals are treated with a lot of love and cared for at this center. The wild animals like tigers, leopards, iguanas, birds, and many species of animals and birds. This place is a must- visit for animal lovers as the rescued wild animals do not attack people and is a place where you can show a lot of love to these wild animals. This is more of a shelter for wild animals and is like a zoo. This animal ark is worth a visit as it provides a unique experience to take care of wild animals and have a close encounter with them.</string>
    <string name="gorewada_short">This is a zoo and a biopark that has a lot of attractions and safaris available at this zoo. You can choose from night safari, African safari, and Indian safari.</string>
    <string name="gorewada_description">This is a zoo and a biopark that has a lot of attractions and safaris available at this zoo. You can choose from night safari, African safari, and Indian safari. This is a great place for getting a closer encounter with animals, spot migratory birds, flora, and fauna. You can enjoy sunsets at this zoo as it looks scenic in the natural setting. An ideal place for nature and wildlife enthusiasts and photographers. There are lakes inside this zoo. You can take a walk in the lush green which looks like a dreamy place with butterflies and a lovely atmosphere. This is a paradise for bird watchers. You can enjoy the view of nature animals, marine life, squirrels, and more</string>
    <string name="rajeev_short">Enjoy an outing getting a close encounter with flora and fauna, and wildlife. It houses many species of animals, birds, reptiles, and more.</string>
    <string name="rajeev_description">Enjoy an outing getting a close encounter with flora and fauna, and wildlife. It houses many species of animals, birds, reptiles, and more. It spans across a land of 130 acres. This is an ideal place for picnics and outings. This is a zoological park that has scenic spots, a lake, and includes endangered species. There is also an animal orphanage at this park where you can have a good time feeding and taking care of orphaned wild animals. There are different zones available at this park where you can watch animals in closed enclosures and from a distance. There are workshops and education programs conducted at this zoo that give you information about animals and their habits.</string>
    <string name="peshwa_short">A popular attraction where you can relax, take pictures of nature and wildlife and enjoy recreational activities.</string>
    <string name="peshwa_description">A popular attraction where you can relax, take pictures of nature and wildlife and enjoy recreational activities. This is one of the popular zoos for family and kids. It is suitable for people of all age groups to spend time and enjoy having a picnic. It has a beautiful garden with a perfect ambiance. A nice place where visitors can have a happy time and spend their time with nature and watching wildlife. There are numerous fun and recreational activities available at this zoo for people of all age groups to enjoy. You can take an adventurous as well as an educational tour with kids at this zoo and learn about the habits and behavior of wild animals. This is the best place to visit for nature and animal lovers. Inside this garden zoo, there is a temple that was built in the 17th century which is dedicated to Lord Ganesha.</string>



    <string name="khadakwasladam">Khadakwasla Dam</string>
    <string name="Bhandaradam">Bhandardara Dam</string>
    <string name="koyna">Koyna Dam</string>
    <string name="jayakwadi">Jayakwadi Dam</string>
    <string name="raigad">Raigad</string>
    <string name="sihngad">Sinhgad</string>
    <string name="pratapgad">Pratapgad</string>
    <string name="panhala">Raigad</string>
    <string name="placenam">placeName</string>
    <string name="placedess">placeDes</string>
    <string name="param1">param1</string>
    <string name="placename">placeName</string>
    <string name="placedes">placeDes</string>
    <string name="shirdi">Shirdi Temple</string>
    <string name="ghrineshwar">Grishneshwar Jyotirlinga</string>
    <string name="Tribak">Trimbakeshwar Jyotirlinga</string>
    <string name="jejuri">Jejuri</string>

    <string name="amte">Amte Animal Park</string>
    <string name="gorewada">Gorewada International Zoo</string>
    <string name="rajivgandhi">Rajeev Gandhi Zoological Parl</string>
    <string name="peshwa">Peshwa Udyan Zoo</string>

</resources>
